前情提要
天黑前必须投降  否则只能见血了
Surrender by nightfall, or this ends with blood.
今天我们都得死
We all die today.
不是非得死  只要有人帮忙
We don't need to die, not if we have help.
欠琼恩·雪诺一条命的人不止你们几个
You're not the only ones who owe your lives to Jon Snow.
我们有孩子了
We're going to have a baby.
他们必将挥师讨伐
A reckoning will come,
我们需要北境的力量
we need the North to face it.
整个北境
The entire North.
我派了一队人马去抓他们
I have a team of men after them.
他们逃不远
They won't get far.
珊莎小姐  危难之际愿奉献我的生命
Lady Sansa, I will give my life for yours if need be.
席恩违背了我的命令
Theon disobeyed my orders.
那小子是个蠢货
The boy's a fool.
也是我的弟弟  他是葛雷乔伊家的人
He is my brother. He's Greyjoy.
卡史塔克家是北方人
Karstarks are North men.
他们永不会忘却杀主之仇
They won't forgive the killing of their Lord.
起来  来打  盲眼女孩
Stand and fight blind girl.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
看来我们一时半会儿去不成维斯特洛了
We won't be sailing to Westeros any time soon.
它们是龙  卡丽熙  永远不会驯服
They're dragons, Khaleesi, they can never be tamed.
你是狼灵  布兰  这存在于你的血脉中
You're a warg, Bran. It's in your blood.
他在等你
He waits for you.
您就是三眼乌鸦
You're the three-eyed raven.
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
第六季 第二集
权力的游戏
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Silmar 草草 潇湘月影
■
翻译：盐湖凉开水 泰斯
校对：泰斯·雪诺 Silmar   顾问：屈畅(ccxx)
时间轴：崽猪 加森 aaaBao Avis
后期：吉吉·波顿  总监：泰斯·雪诺
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
再给他一次机会  奈德
Give him another go, Ned.
是我父亲
That's my father.
和班扬叔叔
And my Uncle Benjen.
举好盾牌  不然我可要把你的头敲得嗡嗡响
Keep your shield up or I'll ring your head like a bell.
他们都好快活
They were all so happy.
你曾经也是
So were you once.
别炫耀了
Stop showing off.
莱安娜
Lyanna!
莱安娜姑妈
My Aunt Lyanna.
我在墓窖里见过她的雕像
I've seen her statue in the crypt.
我父亲从不提她
My father never talked about her.
走开好不好  我们练剑呢
Would you get out of here? We're sparring.
奈德去鹰巢城以后你跟谁练剑
Who are you gonna spar with when Ned goes off to the Eyrie?
不知道
I don't know.
他怎么样
What about him?
威里斯  过来
Wylis, come here.
阿多
Hodor?
可是他有巨人血统
But he's got giant's blood.
你受过训练呀  我看也算旗鼓相当
And you've got training. Sounds like a fair match to me.
班扬出招之前总爱抬下巴
Benjen always lifts his chin when he's about to charge.
闪躲之前又收下巴  小姐
And lowers it when he's going to dodge, my lady.
阿多会说话
Hodor talks?
习武是小主人的事儿  威里斯
You leave the fighting to the little lords, Wylis.
快走  这不是你该来的地方
Come along, now. It's no place for you.
奶妈  看看他这块头
Oh, Nan, look at the size of him.
要是他学了武艺  谁也打不过他
If he ever learned to fight, he'd be unstoppable.
可他永远不会学  因为他是马房小弟
Well, he's never going to learn to fight because he's a stable boy.
别难为他了
So leave him be.
该走了
It is time to go.
请让我多留一会儿
Please, a little longer.
你终于给我看了我想看的
You finally show me something I care about
又要把我拖回来
and then you drag me away.
海底很美
It is beautiful beneath the sea,
但是停留太久就会溺死
but if you stay too long, you'll drown.
我没有溺水  那是我的家
I wasn't drowning. I was home.
威里斯
Wylis.
阿多
Hodor.
我看见你小时候了
I saw you as a boy.
你那时会说话
You could talk.
发生了什么事
What happened?
阿多
Hodor.
梅拉去哪儿了
Where's Meera?
阿多
Hodor.
你不该出来
You shouldn't be here.
洞外不安全
It's not safe outside the cave.
哪里都不安全
It's not safe anywhere.
我看到阿多从前不是这个样子
I saw that Hodor wasn't always Hodor.
-阿多  -他的真名是威里斯
- Hodor. - His real name is Wylis.
他会讲话  会战斗  还...
And he could talk and fight and-- and then--
怎么了
What's wrong?
三眼乌鸦说战争就要来了
The Three-Eyed Raven says there's a war coming.
我们就在洞里参战吗
And we're going to fight it in there?
布兰登·史塔克需要你
Brandon Stark needs you.
需要我做什么  我在洞里干坐着
For what? I sit in there
看他沉迷于各种幻象  无所事事
and I watch him have his visions and nothing ever happens.
他不会永远留在这里
He isn't going to stay here forever.
等他出去  他需要你
And out there he needs you.
时间到了  戴佛斯爵士
It's time, Ser Davos.
开门吧  让两边的兄弟心平气和地见面
Open the door and the men inside can rejoin their brothers in peace.
我们可以放狼出长城  去它该去的地方
We'll even set the wolf free north of the Wall where it belongs.
今晚没必要死人
Nobody needs to die tonight.
战斗从来不是我的强项
I've never been much of a fighter.
抱歉让你们看到这场面
Apologies for what you're about to see.
开始吧
Come on.
进攻
Attack!
打啊  你们这群懦夫
Fight, you cowards!
该死的叛徒
You fucking traitor.
称得上叛徒的
The only traitors here are the ones
是那些用刀子捅死总司令的人
who shoved their knives into their Lord Commander's heart.
几千年来  守夜人军团
For thousands of years the Night's Watch
驻守黑城堡抵挡来犯的野人
has held Castle Black against the wildlings.
到你这儿为止
Until you.
扔进牢里  去他们该去的地方
Throw them into the cells where they belong.
挨了很多刀
Took a lot of knives.
我去叫人准备生火的木柴
I'll have my men get the wood for a fire.
好些尸体要烧
Bodies to burn.
她来了  趾高气扬的瑟曦太后
Right, so there she is, high and mighty Queen Cersei,
奶子和屁股颤悠悠的吹着小风
tits and ass jiggling in the breeze.
忽然  她看着我的方向
All of a sudden she looks my way.
冲我微微一笑  像是在说"怎么着"
Gives me a little smile like, "Well?"
好吧  我这人向来大方
So, all right, you know, I've never been shy
我下面又天赋异禀  我就直接掏了出来
and I'm blessed down south, so I put it right out.
她从未见过那样的风景
She's never seen anything like it.
她见惯了她弟弟的  据我听说
I mean, she's used to her brother and from what I hear,
詹姆·兰尼斯特那儿短得不行
Jaime Lannister's half an inch shy of an inch.
她看了一眼  我发誓  她舔了舔嘴唇
She sees it and I swear to the gods she licks her lips.
你们了解我的
Well, you all know me.
我不会拿这事撒谎
You know I wouldn't lie about this.
给我闪开
Get out of my way.
国王有令  陛下
King's orders, Your Grace.
国王有什么命令
What are the king's orders?
他要您待在红堡里  陛下
He would like you to remain in the Red Keep, Your Grace,
这是为保护您
for your own protection.
你们不许我参加自己女儿的葬礼吗
You're barring me from attending my own daughter's funeral?
原谅我  陛下
Forgive me, Your Grace,
但国王有令  我不能让您过去
by the king's command, I cannot let you pass.
我要跟我儿子谈谈
I would like to speak to my son.
他已经离开了红堡  陛下
He has left the Red Keep, Your Grace.
她长大了
She grew up.
还太年轻
Almost.
抓到杀害崔斯丹王子的凶手了吗
Have we caught Prince Trystane's killers?
我猜是母亲干的吧
I expect it was Mother.
你母亲不会那么做
Your mother wouldn't do that.
她会的
Yes, she would.
你生她的气吗
Are you angry with her?
-当然没有  -那你为什么不许她来
- Of course not. - Then why didn't you let her come?
她完全有权在场
She has every right to be here.
他们说  她不能进大圣堂
They told me she wouldn't be allowed in the sept.
如果她...
If she had tried--
他们别想再把你母亲关回牢里
They're not putting your mother in a cell ever again.
只要有我在
Not while I'm here.
你为什么不去见她
Why haven't you gone to see her?
她承受的一切  都是为了你
Everything she endured, she did it for you.
你以为我不知道吗
Don't you think I know that?
对不起
I'm sorry.
但我不能
But I can't.
为什么
Why not?
战士之子抓住她和玛格丽时
When the Faith Militant seized her and Margaery,
我做了什么
what did I do?
他们像对妓女那样拉她游街时
When they paraded her through the streets like a whore,
我又做了什么
what did I do?
我们都有力不从心的时候
We all fail sometimes.
国王本该是全境守护
The king is supposed to be the Protector of the Realm.
如果我连自己的妻子和母亲都无法守护
If I can't even protect my own wife or my own mother,
我还有什么用
what good am I?
去见你母亲  求她原谅
Go and see your mother and ask her to forgive you.
陛下
Your Grace.
队长大人
Lord Commander.
我想见我妻子
I want to see my wife.
诸神在等待玛格丽王后
The gods wait for Queen Margaery
忏悔罪行  祈求宽恕
to confess her crimes and seek their mercy.
国王也必须等待
The king must wait as well.
去见你母亲吧  托曼
Go and see your mother, Tommen.
你好大的胆子
You're a bold man.
恰恰相反
On the contrary.
我所畏惧的何其之多
I fear a great deal.
天父  圣母
The Father, the Mother,
战士
the Warrior.
知道我们为什么用这石头吗
Do you know why we use these stones?
是为提醒我们不必惧怕死亡
To remind us not to fear death.
我们闭上现世的眼睛  在来世睁开
We close our eyes on this world and open them on the next.
你一定很期待来世吧
You must long for the next life.
说实话  那个我也怕
In truth, I fear that, too.
你囚禁并羞辱我的姐姐
You imprisoned and humiliated my sister.
你姐姐寻求诸神宽恕
Your sister sought the gods' mercy
并赎清了罪孽
and atoned for her sin.
那我的罪孽呢
What about my sins?
我打破了神圣的誓言  从背后一剑杀了我的国王
I broke a sacred oath and stabbed my king in the back.
我杀了自己的血亲
I killed my own cousin.
诸神判我弟弟有罪
When the gods judged my brother guilty,
我却帮他逃脱了制裁
I helped him escape their justice.
我该如何赎罪
What atonement do I deserve?
你要在这神圣之地杀人
You would spill blood in this holy place?
诸神不会介意的
Oh, the gods won't mind.
他们杀的人太多  我们全加在一起也比不上
They've spilled more blood than the rest of us combined.
那来吧
Go on, then.
我活该  我们都活该
I deserve it. We all do.
我们是软弱无能的生灵
We are weak, vain creatures.
我们只因圣母的仁慈而活着
We live only by the Mother's mercy.
如果你指望他们救你  还得靠近些
They should be closer if you mean for them to save you.
不
I don't.
他们在你动手之前不会救我
They'd never reach me before you struck.
以寡敌众我也不是没经历过
I've fought against worse odds.
我们当然会死很多人
No doubt many of us would fall.
但我们是谁
But who are we, hmm?
我们没有名字  没有家人
We have no names, no family.
个个一文不名  无权无势
Every one of us is poor and powerless.
但团结起来
And yet together,
我们可以改天换地
we can overthrow an empire.
母亲
Mother.
他们给她裹的是红袍还是金袍
Did they put her in the red gown or the gold?
金袍
Gold.
很好  金色向来很衬她
Good. It was always her color.
抱歉把您关在这里
I'm sorry for keeping you here.
我不该这么做  但我...
I shouldn't have, but I was--
我不想再次失去您
I didn't want to lose you again.
我明白
I understand.
很高兴见到你
I'm glad to see you.
我知道我该早点来
I know I should have come sooner.
我也想  我错了
I wanted to. I was wrong.
没关系
It's all right.
不  有关系
No, it isn't.
我应该把他们全杀了
I should have executed all of them.
我应该拆了圣堂  砸碎大麻雀的脑袋
I should have pulled down the Sept
不然他们迟早会那样对待您
onto the High Sparrow's head before I let them do that to you,
换作您也会为我这么做
as you would have for me.
您希望把我养育得坚强有力
You raised me to be strong...
而我辜负了您
and I wasn't.
可我希望变得强大
But I want to be.
帮帮我
Help me.
随时随地
Always.
我要是没了命根子  肯定酒不离手
If I lost my cock, I'd drink all the time.
无意冒犯
Meaning no offense.
他开侏儒的玩笑  我开太监的玩笑
He makes dwarf jokes, I make eunuch jokes.
我不开侏儒的玩笑
I do not make dwarf jokes.
你脑子里想了
You think them.
说回船队  全被烧了
So, the fleet. It's been burned.
我们正在抓捕烧船的人
We are searching for the men who burned the ships,
但当时的情况没人知道
but nobody saw anything.
总该有些好消息吧
Surely there's some good news lurking somewhere.
阿斯塔波和渊凯不再请求我们援助了
Astapor and Yunkai have stopped asking us for aid.
也许他们愿意说说自己的小秘密
Perhaps they can tell us their secret.
善主贤主们重新控制了两座城市
The Masters have retaken both cities.
弥林之外  整个奴隶湾
Outside of Meereen, the whole of Slaver's Bay
都回到了奴隶主的手中
has returned to the slavers.
龙怎么样了
What about the dragons?
我们在金字塔底下关着两只呢
We have two of them here beneath the pyramid.
它们不吃东西
They are not eating.
自从丹妮莉丝女王离开  它们就绝食了
They haven't touched any food since Queen Daenerys left.
丹妮莉丝是龙女王
Daenerys is the dragon queen.
显然不能让龙饿着肚子
Can't very well let the dragons starve, that's obvious.
如果龙不想吃  你又如何强迫它们
If a dragon does not want to eat, how do you force him to eat?
龙被关着是长不好的
Dragons do not do well in captivity.
-你怎么知道  -这是我的专长
- How do you know this? - That's what I do.
醉生梦死  无所不知
I drink and I know things.
伊耿用来征服维斯特洛的巨龙
The dragons Aegon used to conquer Westeros
铺天盖地  横跨数百哩
ranged over hundreds of miles.
后来丹妮莉丝的祖先把它们锁起来圈养
Then Daenerys's ancestors started chaining them up in pens.
繁衍了好几代
A few generations later,
最后的龙和猫儿一般大小
the last dragons were no larger than cats.
必须解开枷锁  否则它们会日渐衰弱
They must be unchained or they'll waste away.
弥桑黛
Missandei,
你和那几只龙打过多少次照面
how many times were you in the company of these dragons?
-很多次  -它们伤害过你吗
- Many times. - And did they ever harm you?
从来没有
Never.
龙很聪明
Dragons are intelligent.
有的学士认为  龙比人还聪明
More intelligent than men according to some maesters.
它们亲近朋友  面对敌人则狂暴不安
They have affection for their friends and fury for their enemies.
-我是它们的朋友  -它们知道吗
- I am their friend. - Do they know that?
它们会明白的  是时候请它们吃晚饭了
They will. It's time they had their supper.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
我是你们母亲的朋友
I'm friends with your mother.
我是来帮你们的
I'm here to help.
别把帮手吃了
Don't eat the help.
我小时候
When I was a child,
有个叔叔问我  命名日想要什么礼物
an uncle asked what gift I wanted for my name day.
我求他送我一只龙
I begged him for one of you.
"不必是一只巨龙"  我对他说
"It wouldn't even have to be a big dragon," I told him.
"像我一样小就可以"
"It could be little like me."
所有人哈哈大笑  像是听到了世上最可笑的事
Everyone laughed like it was the funniest thing they had ever heard.
随后我父亲告诉我
Then my father told me
最后一只龙一百年前就死了
the last dragon had died a century ago.
那天晚上  我哭着入睡
I cried myself to sleep that night.
可你们出现了
But here you are.
下次我再冒出这馊主意
Next time I have an idea like that,
照我脸上来一拳
punch me in the face.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
-无名之辈  -我不信
- No one. - I don't believe that.
你自己也不信
You don't believe that.
你是谁
Who are you?
无名之辈
No one.
女孩说出自己的名字
If a girl says her name,
某人让她今晚在屋子里过夜
a man will let her sleep under a roof tonight.
女孩没有名字
A girl has no name.
女孩说出自己的名字
If a girl says her name,
某人今晚给她饭吃
a man will feed her tonight.
女孩没有名字
A girl has no name.
女孩说出自己的名字
If a girl says her name,
某人就把双眼还给她
a man will give her eyes back.
女孩没有名字
A girl has no name.
来
Come.
别管它
Leave it.
女孩不再是乞丐了
A girl is not a beggar anymore.
我们过来的路上看到了尸体
We came upon the bodies on our way here.
六个人  你最好的猎手
Half a dozen men? Your best hunters?
他们显然有帮手
They obviously had help.
我也不认为是珊莎夫人自己把他们全杀了
I didn't think Lady Sansa killed them all by herself.
感谢你的报告  卡史塔克大人
Thank you for this report, Lord Karstark.
我们知道她要去哪儿
We know where she's going.
她哥哥在黑城堡
Her brother's at Castle Black.
奈德·史塔克唯一活着的儿子
Ned Stark's last surviving son?
琼恩·雪诺是私生子  不是史塔克
Jon Snow is a bastard, not a Stark.
我从前也是  父亲
So was I, Father.
只要还有史塔克能从那扇门走进来
Your hold on the North will never be secure
您的北境宝座就坐不稳
as long as a Stark can walk through that door.
黑城堡南面没有防御
Castle Black isn't defended on the southern side.
剩下的人手也算不上守军
And the few men left are barely men at all.
都是乡下小子和盗贼
Farm boys and thieves.
一队人马就能攻下黑城堡  杀死琼恩·雪诺
With a small force, we could storm the castle, kill Jon Snow--
杀害守夜人军团总司令
Murder the Lord Commander of the Night's Watch?
你会让北境所有家族一致对付我们
You'd unite every house in the North against us.
我们不需要北境所有的家族
We don't need every house in the North.
安柏  曼德勒  卡史塔克三家的士兵
The Umbers, the Manderlys, and the Karstarks
比其他家族加起来还多
command more soldiers than all the other houses combined.
有了他们的支持  没人能挑战我们
With their support, none could challenge us.
罗柏国王处决我父亲那天
The Starks lost my house
史塔克家就失去了我们的支持
the day King Robb cut off my father's head.
北境也该换主了
It's time for new blood in the North.
落得疯狗的名声
If you acquire a reputation as a mad dog,
就会被当作疯狗对待
you'll be treated as a mad dog.
拉到后院宰了喂猪
Taken out back and slaughtered for pig feed.
老爷们
My lords.
瓦妲夫人生了
Lady Walda has given birth.
是男孩
A boy.
红脸蛋儿  很健康
Red-cheeked and healthy.
恭喜  波顿大人
My congratulations, Lord Bolton.
恭喜  父亲
Congratulations, Father.
等不及要见我的小弟弟了
I look forward to meeting my new brother.
你永远是我的长子
You'll always be my firstborn.
谢谢您这样说
Thank you for saying that.
这对我意义非凡
It means a great deal to me.
沃肯学士
Maester Wolkan,
给北境所有家族送信  卢斯·波顿死了
send ravens to all the northern houses. Roose Bolton is dead.
被敌人毒杀
Poisoned by our enemies.
他怎么死的
How did he die?
被他的敌人毒死的
Poisoned by his enemies.
你在跟你的领主讲话  用敬语
You're talking to your lord. Use respect.
请原谅  大人
Forgive me, my lord.
传瓦妲夫人和孩子过来
Send for Lady Walda and the baby.
她在休息  大人
She's resting, my lord.
我马上去  大人
At once, my lord.
他来了
There he is.
他漂亮吗
Isn't he wonderful?
我能抱抱他吗
May I hold him?
当...当然
Of-- of course.
小弟弟
Little brother.
波顿大人要见我们
Lord Bolton sent for us.
你看见他了吗
Have you seen him?
当然  跟我来  母亲
Of course. Follow me, Mother.
波顿大人在哪里
Where is Lord Bolton?
安静
Down!
没事  没事
It's all right. Come on, shh.
这里很冷  拉姆斯  我得喂他吃奶
It's cold out here, Ramsay. I need to feed him.
拉姆斯  你父亲在哪儿
Ramsay, where is your father?
拉姆斯
Ramsay.
波顿大人在哪儿
Where is Lord Bolton?
我就是波顿大人
I am Lord Bolton.
拉姆斯
Ramsay.
拉姆斯  求你
Ramsay, please.
我会离开临冬城  回到河间地去
I'll leave Winterfell. I'll go back to the Riverlands.
求你了
Please.
拉姆斯
Ramsay.
他是你弟弟
He's your brother.
我更喜欢做唯一的子嗣
I prefer being an only child.
我看见她跟一个男人在一起
I saw her with a man.
我觉得他并没有伤害她
I don't think he hurt her.
她不想离开那人  那人也不想离开她
She didn't want to leave him, he didn't want to leave her.
你不知道她去哪里了吗
You don't know which way she went?
我找了她整整三天
I spent three days looking for her.
但她消失了
She disappeared.
她看起来怎么样
How'd she look?
还不错
She looked good.
她的打扮不像个淑女
She wasn't exactly dressed like a lady.
她当然不会了
No, she wouldn't be.
在临冬城发生什么事了
What happened at Winterfell?
我本该抓住机会跟你走的
I should have gone with you while I had the chance.
那是个艰难的选择  小姐
It was a difficult choice, my lady.
我们都被迫做出艰难的选择
We've all had to make difficult choices.
我们不该生火
We shouldn't be lighting fires.
不安全
It's not safe.
他不会停止追捕我们的
He won't stop hunting us.
我们只需要坚持到黑城堡
We just have to make it to Castle Black.
只要和琼恩会合  拉姆斯就没法伤害我们了
Once we're with Jon, Ramsay won't be able to touch us.
我一踏进黑城堡的大门就会被琼恩杀掉
Jon will have me killed the moment I step through the gate.
我不会让他那样做
I won't let him.
我会告诉他关于布兰和瑞肯的真相
I'll tell him the truth about Bran and Rickon.
还有我杀了两个农场小子取而代之的真相
And the truth about the farm boys I killed in their place.
我砍掉罗德利克爵士脑袋的真相
And the truth about Ser Rodrik, who I beheaded.
和我背叛罗柏的真相
And the truth about Robb, who I betrayed.
当你披上黑衣  过去的罪行将一笔勾销
When you take the black, all your crimes are forgiven.
我不想一笔勾销
I don't want to be forgiven.
我永远无法弥补对你家人造成的伤害
I can never make amends to your family for the things I've done.
他们会比我更好地保护你
They'll keep you safer than I ever could.
你不跟我们一起走吗
You're not coming with us?
我本想护送你一直到长城脚下
I would have taken you all the way to the Wall.
我做好了牺牲性命的准备
I would have died to get you there.
我可以带一匹马走吗
May I take one of the horses?
你要去哪里
Where will you go?
回家
Home.
葛洛佛家夺回了深林堡
The Glovers have retaken Deepwood Motte.
守卫它的铁民呢
And the ironborn who held it?
他们战至最后一人
They died fighting to a man.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
但是他们死了
But they did
我们的扩张大业也随之破灭
and our invasion died with them.
深林堡是我们在大陆的最后一座要塞
Deepwood Motte was our last stronghold on the mainland.
我们还会有的
Then we will take more.
为什么  就为了松果和石头吗
Why? For more pinecones and rocks?
因为这是我的命令
Because I order it.
我们在大海上无人能敌
We can defeat anyone at sea,
但是面对陆地种的反攻
but we'll never hold lands and castles
我们守不住土地和城堡
against mainland armies.
因为我们的军官违抗我的命令
Not if our captains defy my orders,
擅离职守  在愚蠢的行动中白白牺牲人手
abandon their posts, and sacrifice our men on foolish missions.
我绝不为营救席恩的行动道歉
I won't apologize for trying to rescue Theon.
那他人呢
Then where is he?
您的王国呢
Where is your kingdom?
我们夺占那些城堡是因为北方佬去打仗了
We took those castles because the northerners marched off to war.
而战争已经结束
That war is over.
我们上一次激怒他们的时候
The last time we provoked them too far,
我就在那个窗口  看见他们冲破我们的城墙
I watched from that window as they breached our walls
拆了我们的塔楼
and knocked down our towers.
那天我失去了两个哥哥
I lost two brothers that day.
我失去了三个儿子
And I lost three sons.
五王之战  那是他们的说法
The War of the Five Kings, they call it.
如今其他四个都死了
Well, the other four are dead.
轮到你统治铁群岛的时候
When you rule the Iron Islands,
你尽可以跟他们和平共处
you can wage all the peace you want.
但是现在把嘴闭上  服从我的命令
But for now, shut your mouth and obey
不然我再找一个听话的继承人
or I will make another heir who will.
别挡我的路
Let me pass.
你这个蠢货  快给你的国王让路
You fool, move aside for your king.
我不是一直如此吗  老哥
Haven't I always, brother?
我以为你早在不知哪儿的海底烂掉了呢
I thought you'd be rotting under some foreign sea by now.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
我走后改规矩了吗
Has the custom changed since I've been gone?
你不是应该重复我那句话吗
Aren't you supposed to repeat the words?
你尽管嘲弄我们的神  不用我帮忙
You can mock our god without my help.
我没有嘲弄淹神
I don't mock the Drowned God.
我就是淹神
I am the Drowned God.
从旧镇到魁尔斯
From Oldtown to Qarth,
人们见到我的船就祈祷
when men see my sails, they pray.
你老了  老哥
You're old, brother.
你也辉煌过
You've had your time.
现在时代变了
Now let another rule.
我听说你疯了
I heard you lost your mind
在玉海的风暴之中
during a storm on the Jade Sea.
他们把你绑在桅杆上以防你跳海
They tied you to the mast to keep you from jumping overboard.
是的
They did.
等风暴过了  你就拔了他们的舌头
And when the storm passed, you cut out their tongues.
我需要宁静
I needed silence.
什么样的铁种
What kind of an ironborn
会在风暴中发疯
loses his senses during a storm?
我就是风暴  老哥
I am the storm, brother.
最初也是最后的风暴
The first storm and the last.
你挡我的路了
And you're in my way.
神啊  请带您的仆人回到海浪之下
Lord, take your servant Balon back beneath the waves.
用他的血肉喂养您统辖的生灵
Feed the creatures of your kingdom on his flesh.
让他的骸骨沉到您最深的国度
Pull his bones down to your depths
安息在他的祖先和子孙的身边
to rest beside his ancestors and his children.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
我要查清是谁干的
I'm going to find out who did this.
我要把他们活着扔下去喂鲨鱼
I'm going to feed them to the sharks while they live.
我以盐王座之名发誓
I swear it by the Salt Throne.
你不能以盐王座之名发誓
The Salt Throne is not yours to swear upon,
除非选王会挑中了你
not unless the kingsmoot chooses you.
我父亲肯定希望我来统治
My father would have wanted me to rule.
你父亲尚未做出选择  律法再清楚不过
Your father does not get to choose. The law is clear.
也许你会胜出
Perhaps you'll win.
也许你会成为第一个统领铁种的女人
Perhaps you'll be the first woman in history to rule the ironborn.
也许不会
And perhaps not.
进来
Come in.
抱歉  女士  本不想打扰你
I'm sorry, my lady. Didn't mean to interrupt.
不妨事
You interrupt nothing.
我想你清楚我来的目的
I assume you know why I'm here.
你说了我才清楚
I will after you tell me.
是关于总司令的事
It's about the Lord Commander.
已故的总司令
The former Lord Commander.
只能这样了吗
Does he have to be?
你想要怎样
What are you asking?
你知不知道有什么魔法
Do you know of any magic...
可以帮他
that could help him?
带他回来
Bring him back?
如果你真想帮他  那就别管他
If you want to help him, leave him be.
能行吗
Can it be done?
有些人做得到
There are some with this power.
-怎么做  -我不知道
- How? - I don't know.
你见过吗
Have you seen it done?
我见过一个起死回生的人
I met a man who came back from the dead,
但做法的那个牧师...
but the priest who did it--
原本是不可能的事
it shouldn't have been possible.
可是成功了  现在也能行
But it was. It could be now.
我不行
Not for me.
你不行
Not for you?
我见你饮下本该使你毙命的毒药
I saw you drink poison that should have killed you.
我见你诞下形同影子的魔鬼
I saw you give birth to a demon made of shadows.
我相信的一切
Everything I believed,
在火焰中预见的伟大胜利
the great victory I saw in the flames,
全是假相
all of it was a lie.
一直以来  你都是对的
You were right all along.
真主从未对我说过话
The Lord never spoke to me.
去他的真主
Fuck him, then.
让他们全部滚蛋
Fuck all of them.
我这人并不虔诚  你也看得出来
I'm not a devout man, obviously.
七神  淹神  树神  全都一样
Seven gods, drowned gods, tree gods, it's all the same.
我并非请求光之王帮忙
I'm not asking the Lord of Light for help.
我请求的是在我面前展示过神迹的女人
I'm asking the woman who showed me that miracles exist.
我没有这种能力
I never had this gift.
你试过吗
Have you ever tried?
[瓦雷利亚语]
拜托了
Please.
■
人人美剧APP
看美剧就来人人美剧
更新快 无删减
最大最全的美剧平台
扫码即刻下载
Zimuzu特别推荐
■
各大应用市场均可下载